ABHISHAKE KUMAR BOIIA

□ abhishekbojja9@gmail.com

**** 250-885-2990

♥ Victoria, B.C. Canada

in abojja9

nabojja9

A disciplined and highly motivated computer science graduate with a curious mind and appetite for learning. I have three years of academic and professional experience in revealing hidden insights from data and making useful decisions. I am passionate about machine learning, computer vision and software development.

Skills

LANGUAGES

Python

Java Script

SQL

R

TOOLS/LIBRARIES

Flask

PyTorch

Tensorflow

Docker

Keras

PySpark

Numpy **Pandas**

Scikit-Learn

Git

Anaconda

Amazon Web Services

Scikit-Learn

Fastai

Hadoop

Google Cloud Platform

TECHNICAL

Machine Learning

Full Stack Web Development

Deep Learning

Time Series Analysis

Computer Vision

Natural Language Processing

OPERATING SYSTEMS

Ubuntu

Mac OSX

Windows

Education

University of Victoria M.Sc Computer Science 2019 CGPA- 8/9

Sept. 2017 to Current

Indian Institute of Technology, Dhanbad B.Tech Electronics and Communication Engineering 2015

CGPA - 8.68/10

Aug. 2011 to May 2015

Employment

University of Victoria

Research Assistant, Visual Computing Lab.

Victoria, Canada Sept. 2017 to Current

- Developing algorithms for domain adaptation of semantic segmentation of hands using Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs).
- HandSeg: Developed and open-sourced a large scale dataset containing 200k annotated depth images and deep-learning architectures for hand segmentation. Used SVM based color segmentation techniques to create automatic annotations. Our final model achieves an accuracy of 88% with an inference time of 5 milliseconds/frame on a Nvidia GTX 980 Ti GPU. Technologies used: Tensorflow, Python, OpenCV.

Motion Metrics International

Machine Learning Engineer Intern

Vancouver, Canada May 2019 to Aug. 2019

July 2015 to July 2017

Designed and Developed an end-to-end Deep-Learning based computer vision pipeline to remove shadows from images caused due to varying illumination conditions. The Shadow Removal algorithm I developed has improved the company's existing algorithms performance by 100% and is ready for deployment in production. *Technologies used*: PyTorch, Python, OpenCV, Docker.

India Coal India Limited

Management Trainee Administration of the database server and part of a team that involved in the design of physical database schema, data modeling, and performance tuning. I was part of a research team working on building an Explosive Recommender System, that helps optimize blasting operation to attain production efficiency in coal mines.

Projects

Flack - Real Time Online Messenger Application

Sept. 2019 to Sept. 2019

- Developed an online messaging service using Flask, similar in spirit to Slack. Users can sign in and create or join an existing chatroom, and once a channel is selected, users can communicate in real-time, with the help of WebSockets. The service is deployed on Heroku.
- Technologies: Python, Flask, JavaScript, MySQL, Heroku

Facial Keypoint detection

May 2018 to May 2018

- · Developed a Facial keypoint detection system by training a neural network on Youtube Faces dataset. The system detects the face and identifies 68 facial keypoints.
- *Technologies*: PyTorch, OpenCV, Python.

Movie Recommender System

Feb. 2018 to Apr. 2018

- · Studied and implemented algorithms to predict user ratings for a new movie based on his past ratings for other films using the MovieLens dataset, which contains 100K ratings given by 671 users for about 9.125 movies.
- Evaluated different algorithms on this dataset using root mean square error (RMSE) as a measure and achieved 0.91 on our method.
- · Technologies: Keras, Pandas, Numpy, Python.

Awards

University of Victoria · Graduate Award

University of Victoria · Fellowship

Mar. 2018 Fall 2017

IIT (ISM), Dhanbad · Merit Cum Means Scholarship Awarded for 4 consecutive years for excellent academic performance Aug. 2011